# Gabriel A. Ramírez Segovia

## **About Me**

Technician specialised in the development of applications and web pages. Originally from Spain, I moved to Cork to improve my English and expand my professional skills.

I consider myself a responsible and flexible individual with strong analytical skills and problemsolving abilities, known for my effective performance in team environments

## Contact

(+34) 615 175 633

gabrielramirezsegovia@gmail.com

### Skills

- AngularJS
- Bootstrap
- CSS
- HTML
- Java
- JavaScript
- JSF Primefaces
- MySQL
- PHP
- PHPMyAdmin
- PL/SQL Oracle
- Spring
- Unix

# Languages

**Spanish** 

Native

**English** 

IELTS B2 (2024)

## More information

EU Driver's licence.

## **Work Experience**

#### **Programmer**

Alten | 2022 - 2024

#### **Spanish Air Force**

- Migrated and developed web applications in CI environments using Java 8, Jzee, SVN, Git, Jenkins, Sonar, GitLab, Spring, and JSF with ORM data persistence, Hibernate, and Eclipselink.
- Competently managed relational databases, specifically Oracle, ensuring efficient data handling and retrieval.
- Conducted thorough unit testing, validations, and evidence collection activities using the JUnit5 and Mockito frameworks.

#### **Solutions Assistant**

Everis | 2018 - 2021

#### Mapfre

 Developed new functionalities for the subscription or modification of policies through intermediaries, using AngularJS, Java 8, REST web services, SOAP, Tomcat, and Scrum methodologies with Jira at Mapfre.

#### Vodafone

 Played a crucial role in the creation and development of processes and interfaces within the billing system at Vodafone, using Oracle, PL-SQL, Unix, ShellScript, and Scrum methodologies with Jira.

#### Santa Lucía

 Participated in an introductory course in Angular 7 offered for the client Santa Lucía.

#### Jr. Programmer

Japiend | 2017

- Worked on the design and development of web pages and applications using technologies such as PHP, HTML, CSS and Bootstrap, as well as managing databases with MySQL and PHPMyAdmin.
- Responsible for the creation and publication of multimedia content.

#### Jr. Programmer

Apps-Editor / Estrenos 21 | 2016

- Provided remote user support, managing videoconferences and digital recordings.
- Developed skills in reviewing, repairing and replacing hardware.
- Also performed software installation and configuration with a professional focus.

#### **IT Assistant**

Sermicro 2013

- Provided remote support and assistance to users, managing videoconferences and digital recordings.
- Developed skills in hardware review, repair and replacement.
- Performed software installation and configuration with a professional focus

# **Academic Background**

**Higher Education Certificate in "Multiplatform Application Development".**Centro de Estudios Superiores – Afuera | 2016 - 17

**Higher Education Certificate in "Web Application Development".**Ntra. Sra. del Pilar | 2014 - 16

Medium Education Certificate in "Microcomputer Systems and Networks Technician".

ECFPE. Tomillo | 2011 - 13